Guide to the Paul L. Holmer Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Notes by Holmer, n.d.; Series II
  - Misc. Notes -- untitled paper on anthropology (possibly "What is the 'Self'?), pages 4-21 of a paper on logic (Box 30A, Folder 573)
  - Misc. Notes -- untitled paper questioning the merits of scholarly religious study (1 manuscript, 1 typescript), notes on the creeds (Box 30A, Folder 574)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Virtues and policy," "Christ and the Teacher," "Blessed is He...," "The Pastors We Need," "Occasion of a Wedding," "John Wesley," "Believing stands to knowing," "Re: Christian Liberty," "Community and Crisis: Learning and Understanding," "I Cor. 15:1-10," "Blessed are the pure in heart" (Box 30A, Folder 575)
  - Misc. Notes -- "Works of Soren Kierkegaard," "Criticism," "Kierkegaard - The Present Age," "Philosophy in Scandinavia," "PM Moller," "Shadowgraphs (lecture to Symparanekromenoi)," "The First Love," "What is Theology?" "The Ancient Tragical Motive as Reflected in the Modern," "Elements of Behavior Inevitably," "Real or Ethical Subjectivity," "Topics for Papers," "Ac. to C. of this World," "What is Wisdom?" Kierkegaard and Theology, "The Nature of Theology - S.K.," "Reason - Faith," "Points About Postscript," "S.K. and Some Criticisms of Contemporary Theology," "Subj. Thinker no. 2," "Existence and Reality: The Subj. Thinker (I)" - Handout -- "Assignments: Philosophy 137," "Kierkegaard" [poem by Richard Kell]Letter -- from John Whittaker - Other -- Journal offprint of a bibliography of David F. Swenson's works (Box 30A, Folder 576)
- Course-related material, n.d.; Series III
  - American Philosophical Trends: series of five lectures, includes final examination questions on Philosophical Theology (Box 30, Folder 579)
  - Augsburg Confession: Outlines for a series of 10 lectures (missing lectures 1 and 3) (Box 30, Folder 580)
  - Christian Ethos: outlines for lecture series, ca. 1950s (Box 30, Folder 581)
  - Christian Theology Since Schleiermacher: syllabus for course with above title, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 582)
  - Communication and the Gospel: an outline of three talks on the subject (Box 30, Folder 583)
  - Contemporary Theology: lecture outlines for a series of ten lectures - "Some Reflections About Contemporary Theology," outlines for three parts of a series entitled "Faith of the Christian Church," outline on religious language, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 584)
  - Elements of a Christian Worldview: Religion 23a, Syllabus, mid-term exam, lecture notes on post-reformation thought, middle ages and luther, Christian Faith and the Natural Universe, luther and doctrine, Calvin, Zwingli, Modern Rationalism, 1958 Fall (Box 30, Folder 585)
  - Emotions: Notes from Holmer's lectures on emotion, 1972 Fall (Box 30, Folder 586)
  - Emotions: Lectures given in March 1963 and February 1993, 1963, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 587)
  - Emotions: Syllabi for: Rel. 324 - "Vices and Virtues," Rel. 829a and Rel. 327a -"Emotions, Passions and Feelings," Lecture on "Attitudes" - 10/27/1971; Lecture on "Two Kinds of Learning," notes on related topics (e.g. happiness - humor - irony - etc.), 1971, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 588)
  - Emotions: Updated agenda for Rel. 324 - "Vices and Virtues," one page of essay beginning with "What kind of pastors do we need?" (Box 30, Folder 589)
  - Emotions, Passions and Feelings: Syllabus for Rel 314a, related materials and notes, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 590)
  - Emotions, Passions and Feelings: Rel. 364 / Rel. 327a, Syllabi - Discussion Session Info, Lecture notes (Box 30, Folder 591)
  - Emotions, Passions and Feelings: Rel. 327a Syllabus, notes on emotions, lecture on attitudes (1971), lecture on the existence of God, Review of Grammar of Faith by Robert L. Perkins, Handout "What's Happening in Contemporary Philosophy?", "Remarks on the Occasion of a Marriage", 1971, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 592)
  - Emotions, Passions and Feelings: bibliography of topics relating to emotions - passions - and feelings, Final Examination for Philosophical Theology (Box 30, Folder 593)
  - Ethics, fall 1945: Phil. 11b; Yale University; fall 1945; original file titled "Ethics: Blanshard and Holmer; handwritten lecture notes, typed lecture notes, tests and exams; covers Kant, Mill, and others. (Box 30, Folder 594)
  - Ethics, 1952: Phil. 3 (University of MInnesota), Exam questions, Sermon outlines regarding ethical action/moral obligation, Lecture notes (Box 30, Folder 595)
  - Ethics, n.d. - lectures in ethics, notes on the theory of ethics, and hand-written essays that appear to have been written by Holmer as a student (Box 30, Folder 560)
  - Ethics, n.d. - Practical Reason; Philosophy 3 and 3a syllabus; Ethics [pages 1-44 of lecture outlines]; Definition of Ethics; Reference Books; John Calvin; Bibliography on Ethics; Ethics and the Problems; "Most ethical systems are qualified by other values"; Agenda for this Course; Relevance of an Impossible Ethical Ideal; notes on Christianity and ethics; etc. (Box 30, Folder 561)
  - Ethics, n.d. - Study Questions -- Kant and Mill, on Kant's Fundamental Principles of the Metaphysic of Morals, on Mill's Utilitarianism (Box 30, Folder 562)
  - Ethics, n.d. - Kant and Mill mid-term exam, Questions on Leo Tolstoy's What is Religion? and What is its Essence?, Questions on Tolstoy's My Religion and What I Believe, Student exams (Box 30, Folder 563)
  - Ethics, n.d. -Phil. 120, Study questions, Instructions for take-home exam, notes (Box 30, Folder 564)
  - Faith of the Christian Church -Four lectures in "Faith of the Christian Church" series (Box 30, Folder 565)
  - Grades,Incomplete work from second semester, 1967-1968 (Box 30, Folder 567)
  - Grades for students in Rel 747a, 855a, and a reading course, 1978-1979 (Box 30, Folder 568)
  - Hegel: lecture notes regarding Hegel and the Holy Spirit, "God," "Jesus Christ," and Hegel's religious thought; Handout: "Readings in the Ethics of S.A. Kierkegaard (Box 30, Folder 569)
  - Hegel and Hegelianism: A list of writings by Hegel (by Brad Dewey for Dr. Holmer), Hegal's political philosophy (13 type-written pages), Questions on Hegal, Hegal's view of history, Notes: H. and Monastic Idealism - philosophy of history - etc. Student paper (Jan. 1943) on the "philosophy of religion" (Box 30, Folder 570)
  - History of Philosophy, Ancient: Ancient Philosophy notes: Plato, Aristotle, Pythagoras, the Stoics, etc.; Syllabi for Science and Religion, Logic, and History of Philosophy (Box 30, Folder 571)
  - History of Philosophy, Ancient: Philosophy 141 -- Readings in Classical Texts; Notes for Series of 33 Lectures; Syllabus for Phil. 141; Plato, Aristotle, Lucretius, Cicero, Plotinus, etc. (Box 30, Folder 572)
  - History of Philosophy, Ancient: Philosophy 141 -- Readings in Classical Texts; related notes; Plato, Aristotle, Lucretius, Cicero, Plotinus, etc. (Box 30, Folder 573)
  - History of Philosophy, Ancient and Medieval (2 folders): Phil. 50 and 51, respectively; Thomas Aquinas, Abelard, Anselm; Also some notes on ancient philosophers (e.g. Epicurus, the Stoics); bibliographies for Ancient and Medieval Philosophy (Box 31, Folder 574)
  - History of Religions: hil. 100-f: Required Readings, Suggested Topics for Papers, History of Hinduism, etc. Assignment Sheet - Phil. 180, Assignments - Phil. 11, From the Stone Age to Xianity, Examination - Phil. 11, etc, Report on holdings in the field of Ancient Religion in the University of Minnesota library, yoga instructions, comparative religion, note on religion and its sources, Men of the Old Stone Age, Mohammedanism, supplement: religion and magic - worship and witchcraft (Box 31, Folder 575)
  - History of Religion, fall 1955; World Religions, Spring 1957; Phil. 180; Phil. 11, 1955, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 575)
  - Humanities (from the University of Minnesota) c. 1940s (2 folders)Long memo discussing the rising interest in "the humanities" and its role in education; Study questions and course guide for Humanities 1, "The Humanities in the Modern World"; Exams for humanities courses taught by other professors; Reader guides for major literary works ( The Republic, Don Quixote, etc.); hand-written notes and outlines, ca. 1940s (Box 31, Folder 576)
  - James, William: Questions on James, lecture notes on James (Box 31, Folder 577)
  - Judaism: Living Faiths-A Series of Six Lectures on the Forms of the Spiritual Life, Later Judaism, Judaism Characterized, Judaism: Today, O.T. refers to such sources as..., notes on The People and the Book and Jewish Interp. of the O.T., notes on Exile...History of Jews, The Fall of Palestine, The Prophets, Mosaic Religion, What is Hebrew Religion?, Israel under Independent Kings, Religion of Israel, Chronology of the history of Israel, "Hebraic Religion," Who Are the Hebrews?, notes from Judy Kaufman for Philosophy 11, Summaries of Belief, Life and Teachings of Jesus Christ, Institutional View of Christianity, etc. (Box 31, Folder 578)
  - Kant, Immanuel - Syllabus for Christian Theology Since Schleirmacher, Lecture notes: "The Argument of Kant's Fundamental Principle of the Metaphysics of Morals ," "Kant and Religious Thought," "Kant's Philosophy of Religion" (Box 31, Folder 579)
  - Kant, Immanuel - Syllabus for Christian Theology Since Schleirmacher, notes regarding: Kant's Philosophy of Religion, Prolegomena, Life Events/Dates, etc. (Box 31, Folder 580)
  - Kierkegaard's Edifying Discourses Term paper for Phil. 113s by Edna Larson (Box 31, Folder 581)
  - Kierkegaard Exams, Spring 1946 - completed student exams - including one by G. Lindbeck (Box 31, Folder 582)
  - Kierkegaard on Human Existence, April 1977 -conference at San Francisco Theological Seminary; notes on "What is necessary and what is arbitrary in K.'s thought," "Criteria of adequacy for a docterine of God," "Function of philosophy," "theology reiterated," "Nature of theology" (Box 31, Folder 583)
  - Kierkegaard Resources, n.d. -A list of articles and reviews to supplement lecture material; "James Collins and Kiekegaard" review in manuscript, typescript, and journal off-print form. (Box 31, Folder 584)
  - Kierkegaard Resources, n.d. -Concerning Soren A. Kierkegaard [a list of articles and lengthier reviews to be used as course "supplementary" material]; Reading assignments for "Kierkegaard and Scandinavian Philosoph", Philosophy 137 (Box 31, Folder 585)
  - Kierkegaard Resources, n.d. -Kierkegaard bibliography; readings in S.K.; (both works of Kierkegaard and readings in Kierkegaard studies); hand-written notes (Box 31, Folder 586)
  - Kierkegaard Resources, n.d. -Kierkegaard bibliography; bibliography on Hegel as a background for S.K.; Kierkegaard bibliography -- secondary books; Kierkegaard bibliography -- articles; S.K.: List of Dates and Works; articles by Paul L. Holmer Concerning S.K.; Works of S.K. in order of publication; course assignments; exams (Box 31, Folder 587)
  - Kierkegaard and Nietzsche - Outlines for a lecture series on K. and N. entitled: "The Morphology of Faith"; notes (Box 32, Folder 588)
  - "Learning and Faith," 1957 -A ten-part lecture series (outlines for every lecture except 6 and 10) (Box 32, Folder 589)
  - Lewis, C.S. -CSL - Foundations for Faith; Readings in C.S. Lewis syllabus; Making Sense Christianly; Note About Xianity and Virtue; Theology Virtues; Faith - Hope - Love; About Original Sin and Virtue; About Lewis; Educating Ourselves; Lewis (Box 32, Folder 590)
  - Lewis, C.S. -Lewis Lecture in Honor of William Narum; Syllabus for Reading in C.S. Lewis; Bibliography of the Works of C.S. Lewis; Notes on Consciousness; Article by Narum, "Christian Faith and the Liberal Arts";Article by James Sloan Allen, "Tolstoy's prophesy: 'What Is Art?' Today" (Box 32, Folder 591)
  - Lewis, C.S. -Readings in C.S. Lewis syllabus; Three essays (most likely not written by Lewis) "Man of Prayer," "The Tame Geese: A Revivalistic Meditation," "It Is the Spirit That Giveth Life" (Box 32, Folder 592)
  - Liberal Education -Outline for lecture "What is a Liberal Education?" Former title: "On Understanding the Humanities"; An Abstract/Outline for Reggie Rowell's STM Thesis - "Self-Identity and Religious Identity" (Box 32, Folder 593)
  - Logic Final Examination--Phil. 2, Logic; Logic Examination; corrected logic examinations; hypothetical syllogism; logical form and obverse; Hypothetical Syllogisms; Examination and Answers; Enthymemes; Implication and Inference; Mills Methods Symbollically Presented; Example of Joint Method; Logic: Suggested Readings; Final Examination - Logic 3su; Final Examination - Logic 2A; Propositions; Figures and Moods; Dilemma; Alternative Syllogisms; Logic and Scientific Methods; Syllogistic Forms; Alternative Syllogisms; Logical Fallacies; Logical Problems; A Bibliography on the Philosophy of History; Search for Order; Search for Order; The Nature of Propositions; Term Examination - Feb. 1946; etc (Box 32, Folder 594)
  - Logic - A General Discription of Logic; Logic Problems; two pages of a logic examination; Logical Problems; Answer sheet to a logic examination; etc. (Box 32, Folder 595)
  - Logic - Includes lecture outlines on "nature and scope of logic," "language and logic," "the theory of conceptual meanings," "the theory of propositional meanings," "the theory of inference (reasoning)," "fallacies," "theory of science" (Box 32, Folder 596)
  - Logic -Other examples for Logic course -- newspaper clippings; Suggested Readings; Logical Fallacies (Box 32, Folder 597)
  - Luther, Martin- Course proposal (?) for University of Minnesota - General Extension Division (Box 32, Folder 598)
  - Mill, John S. - John S. Mill's Utilitarianism, General Notes on Mill's Philosophy, Epicureanism, Questions of John S. Mill's Utilitarianism, J.S. Mill: 1806-78, portion of completed exam [?] (Box 32, Folder 599)
  - Misc. Lecture Notes -Augsburg College - Report of Error in Grade Reported for Brad Foss - Oct. 1988; Justice; 9/26/88 Augsburg College - Ethics Class List; Courage; Misgivings; The Logic of Virtue; Comp. and Temperance?; Introduction to Virtues and Vices; Virtue as a capacity; The Virtues; Morals and the Virtues; Vices and Virtues; Introduction: About Vices and Virtues; Popular View; Remarks About 'Virtues' - the concept again; About Temperance; About Justice; Special Notes; About Wisdom; The Christian 'stratagem'; Some theses to be stated...; Dicta about Happiness; Aristotle and Pleasure; About the Concept 'Happiness' (Box 32, Folder 600)
  - Misc. Lecture Notes -Becoming A Human Spirit: Aesthetic And Ethical Considerations -program for The Institute Of Theological And Interdisciplinary Studies, 1996 Fall Series; Becoming a Human Spirit: Esthetic Consideration; Making Sense of Christianity; History of Aesthetic Theory (Box 32, Folder 601)
  - Misc. Lecture Notes -Consciousness and Being a Self; Emotions and Daily Lives; untitled lecture IV; About Norms and the Intellectual Life; 7th Lecture - A Religious Criticism of Common Sense (Box 32, Folder 602)
  - Misc. Lecture Notes -Course leader notes for night school session; memo about an upcoming Yale strike; C.S. Lewis: About Science and Meaningless; C.S. Lewis and Christianity; Notes on Lewis - General; Notes about Lewis; About C.S. Lewis; About Emotion; About Lang. and Literature Again; What Christians Believe; C.S. Lewis: Romance and Rules; The Place of Moral Sensitivity; C.S. Lewis: About His Novels; About Human Nature; Lewis; Function of literature; About Xian Literature; Abolition of Man; Reality, Xianity, and Literature; Happiness; Feelings; Grief [re: C.S. Lewis]; 10 statements about emotions; Language and Expression - Lang. of Rel. and Rel. Life; B.F. Skinner, Sc. and Human Behavior; About Transcendent Emotions; Cognitive Use of Emotion; Expression and Feelings; Is life a comedy?; Emotion and Belief; pages 1-2 of chapter XI The Self and Truth (Box 32, Folder 603)
  - Misc. Lecture Notes -Emotion and Expression; Philosophical Theology Seminar syllabus; Seminar in Philosophical Theology, Topics for Fall Quarter; Science and Religion syllabus; Foundations of Theology; Formless and Theology-less Faith; Xian Teaching and the Emotions; a list of one-line jokes from Jesse Bier's The Rise and Fall of American Humor; notes: "Law of the Spirit of Life..."; Emotions and Belief (Box 32, Folder 604)
  - Misc. Lecture Notes -"Emotions and Seeing the World" (Nov. 2, 1971); Wittgenstein (Sept. 23, 1971); Moral Choice: Decisions and Reasons; Student response to Kierkegaard exam questions (Box 32, Folder 605)
  - Misc. Lecture Notes -"Karl Adam - Our and Holy "; "Paul Tillich"; "Are Psychoanalysis and Religion Compatible?"; "Is Historical Research a Threat to Faith?"; "Romano Guardini"; "Is Relig. Language Meaningful?"; "Heiberg"; "H.H. Rowley - The Unity of the Bible "; Martin Buber; "Bultmann"; "Bultman and the Preacher"; Letter to Mrs. Edward P. Wells on 4 May - 1956 (Box 32, Folder 606)
  - Misc. Lecture Notes -Philosophical Theology Seminar; Science and Religion; Karl Rahner; Phil. of Religion - Seminar - Phil. 233; Assertions; Comments on "Language and Theology: Some Critical Notes"; Hamlet quote (Box 32, Folder 607)
  - Misc. Lecture Notes - "The Problem of Verification in Soren Kierkegaard, Part Five: Conclusion"; Outlines of Lectures on the Subject of "Science and Religion"; Chart: Logical Order (Box 32, Folder 608)
  - Misc. Lecture Notes - "What's the Sense of Calling it the Word of God?"; "Believing the Bible: Superstition and Faith"; Notes on Self/Spirit; Notes on C.S. Lewis;"Grammar of Self"; Essay, "On Concerts and Concert Going," Unknown author (Box 32, Folder 609)
  - Misc. Lecture Notes - "On Reading the Christian Text" - Lecture VIII in a series (Box 32, Folder 610)
  - Philosophy - Introduction to Philosophy Lecture Syllabus; Assignments: Philosophy 137; Ryle -- "The Theory of Meaning," "Ordinary Language," "On Privacy"; Original folder: "Ryle, P..." -- 1965 Hilary Term (Box 33, Folder 611)
  - Philosophy - Introduction to Philosophy Lecture Syllabus (Selected Ethical Problems); Lecture I. "The Nature of Philosophy"; Science and Religion: B. General Characterization of Religion; comments on K.S. Lashley's paper [ The Psychological Review (1922)] in the form of a letter to Lashley (Box 33, Folder 612)
  - Philosophy - Introduction to Philosophy; Outlines to lectures in six units; Readings in Philosophy handouts; notes (Box 33, Folder 613)
  - Philosophy of Religion - Topics for Discussion List, fall and winter quarters, 1959-60; Topics for First Semester of Seminar on Religious Language, 1970; Lecture notes; typescript for S.K. lecture by O. K. Bouwsma (Box 33, Folder 614)
  - Philosophy of Religion - Lecture notes: "Religion and Philosophy" and "Paul Tillich's Life and Literature" (Box 33, Folder 615)
  - Philosophical Theology, c. 1960s (2 folders)Lecture notes taken during the spring semester of 1966; other lecture notes taken 1965, 1966, 1967, 1968; lecture on Whitehead; discussion between Holmer and Daniel Day Williams on Whitehead (Box 33, Folder 616)
  - Philosophical Theology, n.d. - Topics to be covered in Holmer's philosophical theology seminar; Notes on belief (Box 33, Folder 617)
  - Philosophical Theology - Topics to be covered in the second semester of Holmer's philosophical theology seminar (Box 33, Folder 618)
  - Philosophical Theology - Syllabus; notes on Emotions, Feelings, and Belief; Essay "About Consciousness and Psychology" (according to Holmer, these are "comments engendered by reading K.S. Lashley's paper in The Psychological Review (1922)" (Box 33, Folder 619)
  - Philosophical Theology - Philosophical Theology Seminar -- Topics for First Semester; Kierkegaard and Logic notes; Bibliography (Works by S.K., about S.K., related works); Publications of Paul L. Holmer (Box 33, Folder 620)
  - Philosophical Theology - Philosophical Theology Seminar Syllabi; "Ambiguity, Systematic and otherwise"; "Is 'Truth' Systematically Ambiguous?"; Introduction to Philosophy course syllabus -- David F. Swenson, Prof.; Outline of a Course of Lectures on Logic; "Is Truth Systematically Ambiguous?" R.S. 360, Geoff Lilburne; "[J. R.] Lucas on 'Facts'," a paper by Dana Radcliffe; Notes on consciousness/concepts, ambiguity, etc. (Box 33, Folder 621)
  - Religious Language - outline of lecture "The Analysis of Religious Language: Some Considerations" (Box 33, Folder 622)
  - Renaissance and Reformation (History 53), n.d. -Lecture notes; Subjects for topical papers (Box 33, Folder 623)
  - Russian Literature - Life Enrichment Program Notes-Oct. 9, 1995-"Tolstoy and Dostoyevsky"; Reformation and the Person; Schiller's Poems; Leo Tolstoy 1828-1910; Introduction, Leo Tolstoy; Tolstoy, 1828-1910; My Religion; Tolstoy and Human Consciousness; Fyodor in Dostoievsky 1821-81; The Furnace of Doubt; Conversation and Exhaustion of Fr. Zossima; The Furnace of Doubt; lecture VII (Box 33, Folder 624)
  - Schleiermacher -Syllabi "Christian Theology Since Schleiermacher," selected readings, reading questions; "Science and Civilization" handout (Box 33, Folder 625)
  - Notes and letter regarding A Severe Mercy, a book by Sheldon Vanauken [re: C.S. Lewis] (Box 33, Folder 625)
  - Science and Religion - Outlines of lectures on the subject of "Science and Religion" on eight specific topics: "Religion as a Party to Conflict," "General Characterization of Science" (in two parts), "General Characterization of Religion" (in two parts), "Fundamental Categories of the Religious Life," "A Religious Criticism of Common Sense," "Science and Religion and Truth" (Box 33, Folder 626)
  - Science and Religion -Outlines of lectures on the subject of "Science and Religion," same as above; "Learning How to be Religious: The Work of Paul Holmer" an article by Patrick Sherry in Theology, Feb. 1974 (Box 33, Folder 627)
  - Syllabi, Lecture, Outlines, 1954-1957 -University of Minnesota (Bound Volume) (Box 34, Folder 628)
  - Tolstoy as a Christian Writer, fall 1979 - course offered as part of "The Lay School of Religion"; notes on Tolstoy's life; Tolstoy and scripture (Box 34, Folder 629)
  - Vices and Virtues - About Morals and Ethical Theory; Vices and Virtues - Religion 324; Study Questions - Vices and Virtues - Religion 324; Remarks about being 'conceptual'; Remarks about this course of lectures; What Conceptual Schemes Are; topics for vices and virtues course; Questions - Vices, Virtues and Christian Theology; Chapter 97: Virtue and Vices - Introduction; "Aristotle on Justice and Happiness"; Vices and Virtues - Religion 324; Examination on Vices and Virtues; etc. (Box 34, Folder 630)
  - Vices and Virtues -Agenda for 'Vices and Virtues: Religion 324'; Virtues and Knowledge; About Happiness; About Philosophy; Psalms: on Happiness; "The Seven Deadly Sins Today, IV: Avarice or Avaritia" by Henry Fairlie; d. by hand of Nero; "The Seven Deadly Sins Today, IV: Lust or Luxuria"; Wisdom; Opposite is Folly; Othello - After killing his beloved; Charity as Dispositional Virtue; Integrity of Love - Love God and love the neighbor; Note on Knowing the World; etc. (Box 34, Folder 631)
  - Vices and Virtues - Grammar of Vices; About Justice; More About 'Christian' Sins and Virtues; "When pride cometh, then comes shame..."; About Virtues in General"; Agenda for Ethics, Phil. 120; About Virtues in General; Agenda for 'Vices and Virtues: Religion 324'; Augsburg College - class list - fall term 1988; Topic I - Introduction; Various uses of the word 'wrong' (Box 34, Folder 632)
  - Vices and Virtues- Rel. 324; Course Agendas -- two drafts; outlines; notes (Box 34, Folder 633)
  - Von Hugel, Baron - notes on Essays and Addresses, vol. I (Box 34, Folder 634)
  - Wesleyan Theology - lecture notes for theology of John Wesley course; syllabus; final exam; -pages 15-21 of paper "The Role of the Lutheran Church in America in Higher Education" (Box 34, Folder 635)